<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yicong Huang on</title><link>/contributors/yicong-huang/</link><description>Recent content in Yicong Huang on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/contributors/yicong-huang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding R UDF to Texera: The Journey</title><link>/blog/adding-r-udf-to-texera-the-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/adding-r-udf-to-texera-the-journey/</guid><description>Motivation # The R programming language is widely used in many fields, such as bioinformatics, statistical analysis, and social science. Its popularity is driven by its capabilities and the growing demand for data-related work. Given its significance, our goal was to allow users to seamlessly integrate R into Texera workflows.
We want to enhance Texera by extending its support to include R code and facilitating the creation of R user-defined functions (UDFs) for both the table and tuple APIs.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing the UDF Editor by Adding Language Server Support</title><link>/blog/enhancing-the-udf-editor-by-adding-language-server-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 11:38:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>/blog/enhancing-the-udf-editor-by-adding-language-server-support/</guid><description>Motivation # The user-defined function (UDF) operator in Texera plays an important role to allow developers to customize their workflows. The previous implementation of the code editor in the operator can only display the code as plain text (as shown in Figure 1), and it lacks many IDE-like features such as syntax checking and autocomplete. These limitations hinder the productivity of UDF developers. For instance, users often made syntax mistakes that were discovered only when they tried to execute the code.</description></item><item><title>Using Texera to Perform Single-cell RNA Sequencing Analysis with R Language</title><link>/blog/using-texera-to-perform-single-cell-rna-sequencing-analysis-with-r-language/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 14:26:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>/blog/using-texera-to-perform-single-cell-rna-sequencing-analysis-with-r-language/</guid><description>RNA sequence analysis has revolutionized our understanding of gene expression at the single-cell level, providing unprecedented insights into cellular heterogeneity and dynamics. Seurat, a popular R library, has emerged as a versatile toolkit for the comprehensive analysis of single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) data.
While the core engine of Texera is built using Scala, it supports the integration of Python UDFs, allowing users to incorporate custom Python code directly into their data processing pipelines.</description></item></channel></rss>